kramerknives.com 2019-04-19

# Privacy Policy - Kramer Knives

##### Read about Knife Warranties or Returns & Exchanges.

## Privacy Policy

The Privacy Policy applies to personal information that may be collected when you interact with Kramer Knives, Inc. (“Kramer Knives”) and its websites (“Kramer Knives Websites”) at http://www.kramerknives.com/ or at the auction site at https://www.kramerknives.com/product-category/auctions/ (“Auction Site”) and other pages operated by Kramer Knives or by emails with us. Protecting the privacy and security of your personal information is a priority at Kramer Knives, and we believe that a single, comprehensive privacy policy that is straightforward and clear is in the best interests of our customers and our businesses.

By doing business with or interacting with the Kramer Knives Websites or by emails in the manner described in this Privacy Policy at any time on or after the Effective Date, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the application of this Privacy Policy to the collection, storage, use and disclosure of all your personal information as described.

Kramer Knives reserves the right to modify or amend this Privacy Policy at any time, but you can be assured that, should it be necessary to do so, we will post the changes in advance of the time that they become effective.

###### Information automatically collected when you visit our Websites:

When you visit our Websites or send us emails, we automatically record information that your browser or emails provide whenever you visit a Kramer Knives Website or send emails. For example, we may receive and collect: the name of the domain and host from which you access the Internet; the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer you are using; the date and time you access our websites; and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our sites. We use this information to monitor the usage of our websites and as necessary for our business. This information does not include personal information except in the case of emails, we will have your email address and other personal information that you may decide to provide to us.

###### Information collected using cookies:

We use cookies to personalize and enhance your browsing and shopping experience during your sessions with us. Cookies are small files that we place on your computer’s hard drive to collect information about your activities on our Websites. Cookies help us to: (1) speed navigation, keep track of items in your shopping cart and provide you with content that is tailored to you; (2) remember information you gave us so that you don’t have to reenter it; (3) determine the effectiveness of some of our marketing efforts and communications; and (4) monitor the total number of visitors, pages viewed, and the total number of any banners displayed.

Browsers are typically set to create cookies automatically. You can choose to have your browser notify you when cookies are being written to your computer or accessed, or you can disable cookies entirely. If you disable cookies, however, you will not be able to participate in any auctions at the Auction Site, and therefore you will not be able to place bids with us online. Also, by not using cookies, some Kramer Knives Website features and services may not function properly.

Site Analytics: We work with third party service providers to help us better understand how you use our Kramer Knives Websites or to make your email experiences efficient and to determine whether emails are delivered and opened. Our third party service providers will place cookies on your computer to collect information or will track emails and when you open them or will record bounces (non-delivered emails) and sometimes may collect information on the email client. The information that our third party service providers collect will tell us things like which search engine referred you to our websites, how you navigated around our websites, what you purchased and what traffic is driven by banner ads and emails or whether you have opened any emails from us. This information will help us to better serve you and provide you with more personalized information and product offerings. We do not allow our third party service providers to collect your credit card information or password information. Our third party service providers may only use your personal information to perform services for us. Our third party service providers are contractually required to maintain all of the information they collect and analyze for us securely and in confidence. Our third party service providers may not share your personal information with anyone else, or use it for any other purpose, except on an aggregate, non-personal basis. For more information, view our third party service providers’ privacy policies at http://www.campaignmonitor.com/privacy, http://www.domaindiscover.com/help/doc/policies.

Please note that our third party service providers collect data on our Kramer Knives Websites or our emails using first-party data collection. As a result, blocking cookies from third-party domains will not block these first-party cookies. As a user of our Kramer Knives Websites, you may choose to opt-out of this third party’s analysis of your browsing and purchasing behavior on our websites.

To opt-out click here. If you opt-out, you will not be able to use our Auction Site and your account with us will be cancelled.

###### Information collected using pixel tags or clear GIFs:

To help us understand the effectiveness of certain of our communications and marketing efforts, we may use “message format” and “message open” sensing technologies that use pixel tags or clear GIFs (which are also called web beacons). These technologies allow us to know if your e-mail program is able to accept HTML e-mails and, if it is, to: (1) send you e-mails in that format; and (2) determine if you have opened our e-mail messages.

###### Registration at the Auction Site:

At registration for the Auction Site, we will collect personal information. Personal information is your name in combination with other information that we collect about you. For example, personal information will include your first name, last name, address, home phone, email address, billing address, credit card number, expiration date, and security code. We may require additional information for registration.

###### Information collected from outside sources:

We may periodically collect personal information and other information about you from business partners, contractors and other third parties. This includes, but is not limited to, instances in which you affirmatively authorize third parties to provide us with information.

###### Information collected from visitors from outside the United States:

If you are visiting Kramer Knives from outside the United States and provide us with personal information, please note that your personal information will be transferred, stored and processed within the United States. The data protection laws in the United States may not be as comprehensive as those in your country. By doing business or interacting with Kramer Knives, you are consenting to the transfer of your personal information to facilities located in the United States and other facility locations selected by Kramer Knives.

###### Kramer Knives does not knowingly collect personal information from children:

Our Products are marketed for and directed towards purchase by adults or with the consent of adults. Individuals under the age of 18 (“Minors”) are not permitted to use our Auction Site. Should we learn that someone under the age of 18 has provided any personal information to or on any of the Kramer Knives pages, we will remove that information as soon as possible.

###### What do we use your information for?

– To process transactions: Your information will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than the purpose of processing and delivering your order.

– To send periodic emails if you opt to receive such emails: The email address you provide may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates, related information and etc. Please note that when you register for our Auction Site, you must agree to receive all our emails, including those relating to any auctions in which you participate and other emails from us.

– To personalize your experience so as to provide you with a superior customer experience and, as necessary, to administer our business with you.

– To improve our Auction Site for yours and other registered users future uses.

###### Opt-out from the Auction Site:

Even if you later decide to opt-out of the Auction Site, you must notify us by email to: info@kramerknives.com. You may not opt-out to withdraw, change, cancel or otherwise remove yourself from any open auction where you have placed a bid. Even after any opt-out, you may continue to receive e-mails relating to order confirmations, back order notifications, membership information, and/or other business-related communications. Although the primary purpose of these emails is not to provide you with promotional material, they may contain within them some promotional material.

###### How do we protect your information?

Your security while using our website is very important. We take significant and appropriate security measures, including physical, technological and procedural measures, to help to safeguard your personal information and to prevent unauthorized access and disclosure. In addition, we use industry-standard technology, such as firewalls and encryption in the transmission of certain sensitive personal information, designed to prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to your personal information, and, as technology develops, we intend to take additional measures to improve security. Your information is stored and processed on secure servers located in the United States that are protected by physical as well as technological security software.  
For your additional privacy and security, your Kramer Knives Auction account information is protected by a password.  
While Kramer Knives uses accepted industry standards to protect your personal information, no method of transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. While we are focused on the security of your personal information and follow strict standards, processes and procedures that are designed to protect your personal information, we cannot promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information will remain secure in all circumstances.

###### Do we disclose any information to outside parties?

Protecting the privacy and security of your personal information is a priority at Kramer Knives. KRAMER KNIVES DOES NOT SELL OR RENT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES.

###### To Whom Do We Provide Personal Information?

Service providers, subcontractors and agents who perform services on our behalf. We provide personal information to third party service providers, subcontractors, and agents that work under contract on our behalf to provide certain services. These third parties do not have the right to use personal information we provide to them in any way that is not authorized by Kramer Knives. They are contractually obligated to use such information only as necessary to assist us and to maintain the confidentiality and security of such information.

Credit Card Companies. Credit card transactions are handled by third party financial institutions and their vendors and contractors who receive credit card numbers and other personal information from us to verify the credit card numbers and process transactions.  
Law enforcement officials and as required by law. Kramer Knives may release personal information to third parties when we determine, in our judgment, that it is necessary to (a) comply with the law, regulation, legal process, or enforceable governmental request; (b) enforce or apply the terms of any of our policies or user agreements; or (c) protect the rights, property or safety of Kramer Knives, our employees, our customers, users, or others.

Sales, Mergers, and Acquisitions. If Kramer Knives becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, personal information may be provided to the entities and advisors involved subject to a confidentiality agreement, and we will provide notice before any personal information is finally transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

To Fulfill Accepted Winning Bids. In order to complete your transaction if you are a winning bidder and your bid is accepted at our Auction Site, we may need to forward your name, email address, and shipping or billing address for shipping and handling purposes.

###### Third Party Websites and Web-Tracking:

If we have links to third party Websites or if we have third party advertisements and you choose to click on such links to view third party sites, such third parties may place or access cookies on your computer. If you would like to learn more about the third party advertisers that may be aware of the fact that you visit Kramer Knives websites, and to understand your choices about having such advertisers’ cookies turned off, please visit www.networkadvertising.org. Please understand that Kramer Knives does not control these third party cookies, and you should check the privacy policy of the Internet advertising company or advertiser to see whether and how it uses cookies.

Whenever you click on links and banners on the Kramer Knives website that take you to a third party website, you will be subject to the third party’s privacy policies, not Kramer Knives’. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Kramer Knives.

###### Online Privacy Policy Only:

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our Kramer Knives Websites or through emails and not to information collected offline.

###### Terms and Conditions:

Please visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website, click here. Our warranty policies can be viewed by clicking here.

###### Changes to our Privacy Policy:

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page.  
This policy was last modified on January 18, 2018.

###### Whom do I contact if I have questions or concerns?

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:  
Kramer Knives, Inc.  
[360.738.6004](tel:\(360\)%20738-6004)  
info@kramerknives.com

###### Contacting Customer Service:

When you contact customer service, we may ask you to provide, or confirm, personal information so that we can better serve you.
